Evan Madden

(267) 314 - 7267 | <u>evan.madden@gmail.com</u> | Philadelphia, PA 19148 Portfolio: https://github.com/EvMad GitHub: /EvMad

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/evan-madden-923474211/

Summary:

Evan is a full stack web developer with a customer service background. His primary strengths are in organizing information, resources, and people. Evan's technical strong points are in CSS frameworks, JavaScript and JS server-side extensions, as well as both relational and non-relational databases. Evan is currently pivoting his career to intersect web development with a robust client experience skillset. Evan's background is in the music and food and beverage industries.

Current Goals:

Evan is pursuing a new career path in web development, fueled by a passion for music and entertainment. His goal is to apply what he has learned to the things that he loves doing.

Technical Skills, Languages, and Applications:

MongoDB, Git Bash, Node, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, JQuery, JavaScript, JS, Handlebars, HTML, Insomnia Core, Heroku, Cloudinary, Adobe XD

Current Projects:

Community Canvas

https://quiet-oasis-46946.herokuapp.com/

Community Canvas is a full stack application developed for users to upload and view photos of street art in their city and around the world. This project role focused on learning how to use Cloudinary as a digital assets management platform, and incorporating cloud capabilities into the application. Developed in a boot camp group project setting, the application will be expanded to utilize the Open Maps API to associate photo uploads to specific map coordinates.

BandFinder

https://keith-l-watford.github.io/artists-and-bands/

This group collaboration utilizes API's from Ticket Master and the music service Deezer to provide search data on upcoming live music events by area, plus links to artist information and playlists. This project role focused on using Bulma to create a streamlined and mobile-responsive user interface, as well as handling JQuery, JavaScript, and HTML.

Riff Lifter Touring

A new site for Riff Lifter Touring, including a directory for various musicians' services, and a legacy archive of past tours and projects. The site includes profiles of various musicians, and utilizes various API's to feed live music event information to the page. Built with JavaScript, CSS, and Handlebars JS.

Relevant Employment:

Kung Fu Necktie March 2015-Present

Live Music Venue in Philadelphia, PA
-Bar manager
-Concert Promoter and Show Runner
-Responsible for coordinating artists, sound techs, security, and bar staff.
-Manage ticket sales, targeted ad promotion, and curated VIP ticket experiences

Riff Lifter Touring

Feb 2011 - Feb 2018

Full service booking agency run remotely.

-Booking Agent for North America

-Utilized Spreadsheets to estimate and track gas mileage and tour budget

-Stored and managed crucial artist data such as concert attendance, fees, and expenses

-Coordinated travel, crew, international visas, tour routing, and venue communication

-Acting tour manager handling daily contacts and day sheets, and public relations by region

Education:

BCS Coding Bootcamp University of Pennsylvania May 2021 - August 2021

BA in Music, Recording Emphasis University of Maryland Baltimore County Aug 2000 - May 2004